When it happens... there's nothing like it!
Sunshine on Leith is a music, comedy, drama film directed by Dexter Fletcher.
Davy and Ally have to re-learn how to live life in Edinburgh
after coming home from serving in Afghanistan.
Both struggle to learn to live a life outside the army and to deal with
the everyday struggles of family, jobs and relationships.
Sunshine on Leith is based on the sensational stage hit of the same
name, featuring music by pop-folk band The Proclaimers.
Davy Henshaw, played by George MacKay.
Ally, played by Kevin Guthrie.
Ronnie, played by Paul Brannigan.
Jean Henshaw, played by Jane Horrocks.
Robert 'Rab' Henshaw, played by Peter Mullan.
Liz Henshaw, played by Freya Mavor.
Sunshine on Leith is a 2013 Scottish romantic
musical film directed by Dexter Fletcher.
It is an adaptation of the stage musical of the same name, a
jukebox musical featuring songs by the Proclaimers.
It was screened in the Special Presentation section at the
2013 Toronto International Film Festival.
The songs, arranged by musical director Paul
Englishby, are performed by the cast.
The Proclaimers themselves appear in a brief cameo.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.